Jacob C. Lutz

jacob@colemanlutz.com

Software Development

Entry-level software developer who takes pride in craftsmanship of quality software. Possesses working knowledge of Object Orientation Programming and source control. Has worked in C++, C#, Ada, Java, Ruby, HTML, and CSS, and is familiar with Debian-based distributions of Linux OS.

Education

Indiana Institute of Technology Fort Wayne, IN
Bachelor of Science, *Software Engineering* May 2015
Minor in *Networking* GPA 3.8/4.0

Professional Experience

Liberty Mutual Insurance

June 2015 – Present

Information Technology Analyst

• Work on building the new online insurance quoting application.

Nexus Technology Partners

August 2013 – August 2014

A professional information technology consulting company located in downtown Fort Wayne, IN, whose main purpose is to provide businesses with IT advice and support.

Software Development Intern

- Worked on creating a public key encryption infrastructure to be used for employee authentication
- Created and maintained Subversion source control server
- Provided training on using source control
- Recovered and secured client websites
- Provided Windows 8 support

Professional Teaching Experience Indiana Institute of Technology

Lab Assistant August 2014 – May 2015

- Oversaw Automation Lab
- Taught students to use high-level scripting languages to control machinery

Teaching Assistant

August 2013 – December 2013

- Helped create curriculum for freshman Computer Science majors
- Presented weekly on introductory computer science topics

Certifications/Student Organizations

Member of Indiana Tech Resident Assistant Staff
 Treasurer of Indiana Tech Student Ambassadors
 Member of Indiana Tech Collegiate Cyber Defense Team
 Vice President of Indiana Tech Collegiate Cyber Defense Club
 August 2013 – May 2015
 August 2012 – October 2013
 August 2013 – May 2014

- Control of material rections of the state of the state

CompTIA Net+ Certification December 2011
CompTIA A+ Certification May 2011